<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DSPG 2020</title>
    <link>/dspg20loudon/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DSPG 2020</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/dspg20loudon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Results Section One</title>
      <link>/dspg20loudon/findings/knitted_demographics_loudon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20loudon/findings/knitted_demographics_loudon/</guid>
      <description>Loudoun County is part of the northern Virginia region. Along with Loudoun County, the NoVA area is composed of:
 City of Alexandria Arlington County City of Fairfax Fairfax county City of Falls Church Fauquier County Loudoun County City of Manassas City of Manassas Park Prince William County  Recognizing that food insecurity is not bound by county or city, we constructed social and economic vulnerability indices for NOVA at the census tract levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results Section Two</title>
      <link>/dspg20loudon/findings/foodaccessmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20loudon/findings/foodaccessmaps/</guid>
      <description>Food insecurity may also be affected by food accessibility. Those with access to high quality food outlets were less likely to be food insecure (Mayer, Hillier, Bachhuber and Long, 2014). We measured food access in the Loudoun County and northern Virginia area using three indicators. These indicators correspond to traditional food retailers, farmers’ markets, and food pantries. Unlike traditional food retailers and farmers’ markets, food pantries usually provide food to vulnerable populations for free or at especially discounted prices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results Section Three</title>
      <link>/dspg20loudon/findings/results-section-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20loudon/findings/results-section-three/</guid>
      <description>Project goals The goal of this project was to identify areas in Loudoun County and northern Virginia where a potential Loudoun County food hub could alleviate food insecurity. As we have shown in the preceding sections, there are many variables related to food security and these variables are often correlated with one another. In this final section, we construct a single composite index variable for food insecurity which can be used to identify food insecure areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/dspg20loudon/methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20loudon/methods/</guid>
      <description>Data and Methodology  Matson and Thayer (2014) note that food hubs can decrease food insecurity. In assessing the potential for a Loudoun County food hub to address such issues, we first identified food insecure areas in the Loudoun County region. We used two primary data sources for this project. To develop index variables of food insecurity, we obtained underlying variables on food supply and demand in Loudoun County and the northern Virginia region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/dspg20loudon/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20loudon/overview/</guid>
      <description>2020 Loudoun County Project We partnered with Virginia Cooperative Extension to assess the potential for a Loudoun County food hub to alleviate food insecurity in northern Virginia and provide a sales outlet for local agricultural products.
Project Goals Our project goal was to create a composite index measuring food insecurity in Loudoun County and northern Virginia to identify areas where a food hub could improve food and nutrition outcomes.
Project Approach Our research team used an interdisciplinary approach to combine datasets of publicly available economic and social information related to food insecurity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/dspg20loudon/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20loudon/readme/</guid>
      <description>Loudoun_website This repository contains the website for DSPG 2020 Loudoun county project
To add contents  Edit .md files in content directory Edit config.toml to modify the home page add images in content/images  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> </title>
      <link>/dspg20loudon/team1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20loudon/team1/</guid>
      <description>Data Science for the Public Good Program  The Data Science for the Public Good (DSPG) Young Scholars program is a summer immersive program held at the Biocomplexity Institute’s Social and Decision Analytics division (SDAD). In its seventh year, the program engages students from across the country to work together on projects that address state, federal, and local government challenges around critical social issues relevant in the world today.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>