<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UVA Biocomplexity Institute</title>
    <link>/DSPG2020_ARI2/</link>
    <description>Recent content on UVA Biocomplexity Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/DSPG2020_ARI2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Job Performance Scales</title>
      <link>/DSPG2020_ARI2/findings/performance_tidy_text/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/DSPG2020_ARI2/findings/performance_tidy_text/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  Approach Once we compiled a collection of papers addressing job performance, we extracted scales from those that contained measurement items. The following table displays the scales we collected. Before we began topic modeling, we wanted to get a sense of the sources and content of the scale items.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latent Dirichlet Allocation Modeling of Performance Scales</title>
      <link>/DSPG2020_ARI2/findings/performance_lda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/DSPG2020_ARI2/findings/performance_lda/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  Approach Once we gathered a sufficient number of scales from a variety of sources, we analyzed these scales using topic modeling to identify underlying themes from across the corpus. Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA) is a probabilistic topic modeling process which considers each document as a distribution of topics and each topic as a distribution of words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARI Individual Performance 2020 Summer Project</title>
      <link>/DSPG2020_ARI2/methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/DSPG2020_ARI2/methods/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  Data and Methods In order to provide our stakeholder, the Army Research Institute, with pertinent insight regarding the feasibility of predicting behavioral performance using existing data sources we must first identify existing authoritative behavioral performance items from academic, industry, government and military sources. In essence, the collection of this corpus of documents will serve as the basis from which a consensus regarding themes and topics relating to behavioral performance will be extracted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARI Individual Performance 2020 Summer Project</title>
      <link>/DSPG2020_ARI2/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/DSPG2020_ARI2/overview/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  Project Overview According to the Data Manpower Data Center (DMDC) the United States Army employs approximately 475 thousand active duty, and approximately 190 thousand reserve, service members. As part of its standard personnel management practices it collects a number of measures and/or surveys from and about these service members. Given the scope, depth, duration of this data source, the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARI Individual Performance 2020 Summer Project</title>
      <link>/DSPG2020_ARI2/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/DSPG2020_ARI2/team/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  UVA Data Science for the Public Good The Data Science for the Public Good (DSPG) Young Scholars program is a summer immersive program held at the Biocomplexity Institute’s Social and Decision Analytics division (SDAD). In its seventh year, the program engages students from across the country to work together on projects that address state, federal, and local government challenges around critical social issues relevant in the world today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biterm Modeling of Performance Scales</title>
      <link>/DSPG2020_ARI2/findings/biterm_markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/DSPG2020_ARI2/findings/biterm_markdown/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  About BTM Biterm Topic Modeling (BTM) is a method of detecting the topics occurring in short texts. In other approaches to topic modeling, each document is analyzed for topic occurrences within that document. The challenge with applying traditional topic modeling techniques to short documents is that there is not enough data to work with.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>