<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DSPG 2020</title>
    <link>/dspg20richmond/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DSPG 2020</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/dspg20richmond/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Results Section One</title>
      <link>/dspg20richmond/findings/results-section-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20richmond/findings/results-section-one/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  Modeling Census Tract Level Evictions: Correlates Of Eviction Rates The sociodemographic variables shown, including race and income, mirror the spatial relationships seen in eviction rates. In this section, we use a regression model to study whether and how eviction rates are affected by these variables. We find that the following variables are significantly associated with eviction rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Evictions in Richmond City: Policy, Community, and Individual Factors</title>
      <link>/dspg20richmond/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20richmond/overview/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  The city of Richmond has one of the highest eviction rates in the United States. The VT DSPG team used publicly available data to characterize areas of high eviction need in Richmond. This project aims to help Virginia Cooperative Extension (VCE) carefully target their financial literacy programs to the areas of highest need within the city of Richmond.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results Section Two</title>
      <link>/dspg20richmond/findings/results-section-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20richmond/findings/results-section-two/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  ##Modeling Census Tract Level Evictions : Richmond: Visualizing An Index Of Eviction Intensity
The Eviction Intensity Index we created from our regression model was used to rank all census tracts in U.S. cities that are comparable in size to Richmond. The word cloud below visualizes the frequency that census tracts with the words “Richmond City” show up in a list of the top 320 most eviction intense tracts in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results Section Three</title>
      <link>/dspg20richmond/findings/results-section-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20richmond/findings/results-section-three/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  ##Modeling Census Tract Level Evictions: Visualization of Socio-Demographic Variables and Eviction Rates in Richmond 2013-2018
To provide further guidance for policymakers interested in understanding evictions in Richmond, we provide a collection of dashboards that can be used to visualize the socio-demographic variables that our statistical model identified as being associated with eviction rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> </title>
      <link>/dspg20richmond/methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20richmond/methods/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  Data Data was collected and joined on tract GEOID across the following sources:
 2013-2017 American Community Survey: highest educational attainment, unemployment. Missouri Census Data Center’s 2018 Geocorr database to understand tracts in terms of their corresponding census places, namely cities. Eviction Lab at Princeton University: Census tract-level data on eviction rates, poverty rate, median income, and race.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conclusion</title>
      <link>/dspg20richmond/findings/results-section-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20richmond/findings/results-section-four/</guid>
      <description>We determined that state level landlord and tenant friendly policies are significantly associated with tract-level eviction rates. These finding suggested that state level policy levers such as:
 Laws that reduce protected class exemptions in housing-related transactions, Laws that protect tenants from retaliation by landlords Laws that reduce the number of exemptions landlords have from state landlord-tenant law  can affect evictions rates.
Positive values of the eviction intensity indicator show there are still census tracts where eviction rates are not fully explained by sociodemographic and state level policy variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> </title>
      <link>/dspg20richmond/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20richmond/team/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  Data Science for the Public Good Program The Data Science for the Public Good (DSPG) Young Scholars program is a summer immersive program held at the Biocomplexity Institute’s Social and Decision Analytics division (SDAD). In its seventh year, the program engages students from across the country to work together on projects that address state, federal, and local government challenges around critical social issues relevant in the world today.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>