<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UVA Biocomplexity Institute</title>
    <link>/dspg20career/</link>
    <description>Recent content on UVA Biocomplexity Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/dspg20career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Results Overview</title>
      <link>/dspg20career/findings/general-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20career/findings/general-overview/</guid>
      <description>.imgContainer{ float:left; }  Main Findings From our research, we have come to several major findings.
Data profiling, benchmarking, and exploration. 1. BGT resume data overrepresents young and white collar veterans.    Figure 1. Results from data benchmarking using Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System, American Community Survey, Veterans Employment Outcomes, and BGT Resume data. In both graphs, BGT observations are in orange. These findings show BGT over estimates white collar veterans by comparison, for both education and industry variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Benchmarking</title>
      <link>/dspg20career/findings/results-section-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20career/findings/results-section-one/</guid>
      <description>In order to better understand the Burning Glass resume data, particularly in the context of veterans in the DC metro area, we wanted to benchmark it against other veteran- and career-related datasets to understand any differences in the populations. For more details about the data sources used here, see the Data section.
Veterans Employment Outcomes (VEO) comparison with BGT data The following plot compares the percentage of veterans in a given career for veterans nationally (in the Veterans Employment Outcomes data) and veterans in the BGT data (for the DC Metropolitan Statistical Area).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sequence Exploration</title>
      <link>/dspg20career/findings/results-section-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20career/findings/results-section-two/</guid>
      <description>Exploring veteran’s whole career sequences After cleaning the BGT data, we created our sequence objects using TraMineR. To begin, we created a sequence object using the whole career of veterans. This yielded 8,068 sequences of varying lengths. When creating the whole career sequence object, we defined eight unique states: Zone 1, Zone 2, Zone 3, Zone 4, Zone 5, Missing zone, Military, Military transition unemployment, Civilian unemployment, and Retired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sequence Clustering</title>
      <link>/dspg20career/findings/results-section-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20career/findings/results-section-clustering/</guid>
      <description>In the previous Sequence Exploration, we introduced the following sequence state naming system, shown in Table 1.
 {&#34;x&#34;:{&#34;filter&#34;:&#34;none&#34;,&#34;data&#34;:[[&#34;Zone 1&#34;,&#34;Zone 2&#34;,&#34;Zone 3&#34;,&#34;Zone 4&#34;,&#34;Zone 5&#34;,&#34;Missing zone&#34;,&#34;Military&#34;,&#34;Military transition unemployed&#34;,&#34;Civilian unemployed&#34;,&#34;Retired&#34;],[&#34;O*NET SOC Code&#34;,&#34;O*NET SOC Code&#34;,&#34;O*NET SOC Code&#34;,&#34;O*NET SOC Code&#34;,&#34;O*NET SOC Code&#34;,&#34;O*NET SOC Code&#34;,&#34;O*NET SOC Code&#34;,&#34;seqdef() left =&#34;,&#34;seqdef() gaps =&#34;,&#34;seqdef() right =&#34;],[&#34;Some of these occupations may require a high school diploma or GED certificate. Little or no previous work-related skill, knowledge, or experience is needed for these occupations&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/dspg20career/data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20career/data/</guid>
      <description>2020 Veteran Career Pathways Summer Project Data Sources Burning Glass Technologies Resume Data Burning Glass Technologies (BGT) provides data on resumes that were collected from publically available sites between 2016 and 2018. This data includes information about an individual&amp;rsquo;s education, certifications, skills, geographic location, and of course, job history. The information on job history includes position of each job on the resume, the dates the job was held, and the Occupational Information Network (O*NET) Standard Occupation Classification (SOC) code of the job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/dspg20career/methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20career/methods/</guid>
      <description>2020 Veteran Career Pathways Summer Project Methodology Data Cleaning and Profiling In order to get the resumes from veterans in the DC Metropolitan Statistical Area (MSA), we first profiled the data to better understand and address the completeness, potential for duplication, and valid values of the Burning Glass Technologies resume data. In addition to filtering observations to include a reported MSA of 47900 (the code for the DC-VA-MD-WV Metropolitan Statistical Area), we also checked to see if individuals reported living in a zip code that fell in the DC MSA, and ensured that none of the entries were duplicates based on the resume&amp;rsquo;s unique ID.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/dspg20career/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20career/overview/</guid>
      <description>2020 Veteran Career Pathways Summer Project This project focuses on exploring the career pathways of Army veterans, observed using Burning Glass Technologies resume data. The team explores modeling techniques including sequence analysis and tournament models to classify resume data into a typology of career trajectories, and identify factors associated with career mobility. Initial modeling efforts are focused on resumes in the Washington Metropolitan area.
Project Goals As part of a larger project with the Army Research Institute we seek to develop predictive models and metrics to describe the career pathways of veterans and active duty Soldiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/dspg20career/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20career/team/</guid>
      <description>UVA Data Science for the Public Good Program The Data Science for the Public Good (DSPG) Young Scholars program is a summer immersive program held at the Biocomplexity Institute’s Social and Decision Analytics division (SDAD). In its seventh year, the program engages students from across the country to work together on projects that address state, federal, and local government challenges around critical social issues relevant in the world today. DSPG young scholars conduct research at the intersection of statistics, computation, and the social sciences to determine how information generated within every community can be leveraged to improve quality of life and inform public policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tournament Theory</title>
      <link>/dspg20career/findings/results-section-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dspg20career/findings/results-section-four/</guid>
      <description>Tournament Theory Rosenbaum’s (1979) tournament model (described in more detail in the Methodology section) argues that career mobility can be represented as rounds of a tournament, where each round has winners and losers and the results of each round affect subsequent career opportunities. We use 10-year career sequences of veterans beginning after their last military job to test hypotheses about career mobility.
We are particularly interested in two potential tournament “results” for veterans: early promotion (promotion within two years of leaving the military) and transitional unemployment (unemployment occurring directly after leaving the military).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>